From nothing comes a King
King Arthur: Legend of the Sword is a action, drama,
fantasy film directed by Guy Ritchie.
When the child Arthur’s father is murdered,
Vortigern, Arthur’s uncle, seizes the crown.
Robbed of his birthright and with no idea who he truly is, Arthur
comes up the hard way in the back alleys of the city.
But once he pulls the sword Excalibur from the stone, his life is turned
upside down and he is forced to acknowledge his true legacy...
whether he likes it or not.
Arthur, played by Charlie Hunnam.
Vortigern, played by Jude Law.
The Mage, played by Àstrid Bergès-Frisbey.
Uther Pendragon, played by Eric Bana.
Bedivere, played by Djimon Hounsou.
William "Goosefat Bill", played by Aidan Gillen.
King Arthur: Legend of the Sword is a 2017 epic fantasy action-adventure film directed by Guy Ritchie, who co-wrote the film
with Joby Harold and Lionel Wigram from a story by Harold and David Dobkin, inspired by Arthurian legends.
The film tells the origin story of King Arthur, played by Charlie Hunnam, a man who discovers his lineage after taking the sword in
the stone, and teams up with a group of rebels to face against the tyrannical king Vortigern, played by Jude Law.
Àstrid Bergès-Frisbey, Djimon Hounsou, Aidan Gillen,
and Eric Bana star in supporting roles.
King Arthur: Legend of the Sword premiered at the TCL Chinese Theater on 8 May 2017 and was
theatrically released on 12 May 2017 in the United States and 19 May 2017 in the United Kingdom.
The film received mixed reviews and grossed $148.7 million
worldwide against its $175 million production budget.
Originally, the film was meant to be the first in a six-film franchise, but the planned sequels
were cancelled after it underperformed at the box office and lost Warner Bros.
Pictures and Village Roadshow Pictures over $150 million.
The film explores themes of sword, legend, camelot, knight, king arthur.
The tone is emotional.